MANPREET LAKHAN

SENIOR PRODUCT MANAGER

224.659.0262



mklakhan@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/manpreetlakhan



Chicago, IL



EDUCATION

MASTER'S DEGREE

Georgetown University Technology Management 2015 - 2017

BACHELOR'S DEGREE

University of Illinois at Chicago Psychology 2002 - 2006

EXPERTISE

Product Management
Business Analysis
Project Management
Strategy & Planning
Marketing & Communication
User Experience & Research
Competitive Analysis
Release Management
Agile Scrum Methodology

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Customer focused Senior Product Manager with 6 years of direct experience in product management and over 4 years in business analysis and project management for multimillion-dollar initiatives. Previous work includes products funded by the National Institutes of Health (NIH), Health Care Service Corporation (HCSC), United Airlines, and Publicis Groupe. Currently employed as a product lead for the Transportation & Federal verticals at Uptake, a Chicago-based startup, specializing in industrial IoT & offering predictive analytics through SaaS.

EXPERIENCE

UPTAKE

Senior Product Manager | May 2018 - Present

Own product roadmap, vision, strategy and execution for the Transportation and Federal verticals at Uptake, aimed at optimizing asset performance & reducing failures through predictive insights.

- Lead multiple teams across Customer Success, Data Science, User Experience, Engineering, Marketing, & Sales to launch product experiences that exceed user goals, validated through direct feedback, adoption, & usage
- Owned and released two products providing \$5M in annual value opportunity to customers over the last 12 months
- Led initiative to create clear and measurable KPIs via model performance tracking, resulting in an improvement of data science models & insight precision to over 90%
- Partner with cross-functional leaders to refine practices, resolve conflicts, and remove impediments for product development teams allowing for rapid prototyping, feedback, & prioritization

PERFORMICS-PUBLICIS GROUPE

Director, Product Management | January 2018 – May 2018 Associate Director, Product Management | January 2016 – January 2018 Product Manager | March 2014 – January 2016

Created, managed and evolved product strategies for Publicis Groupe's proprietary digital analytics tools, leveraged in winning and maintaining major global brands for over 100 media agencies worldwide.

- Managed a team of Product, User Experience, Business Development and Customer Success Managers to execute on data driven roadmaps that resulted in increased adoption & usage by 150% (over 4 years)
- Led a complete product redesign from inception to in market that was rated by users as significantly more valuable than the previous version
- Led design of advanced monitoring tools to identify data collection issues resulting in reduction of troubleshooting hours by 75%

TOOLS

Microsoft Suite

Balsamiq

Jira

Rally

Aha!

CERTIFICATIONS

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT Northwestern University

Northwestern University Fall 2020 - Present

BUSINESS ANALYSIS Northwestern University Spring 2012

INFORMATION SYSTEMS
PROJECT MANAGEMENT
Northwestern University
Fall 2010

EXPERIENCE CONTINUED

UNITED AIRLINES/APEX SYSTEMS

Sr. Business Analyst | March 2013-March 2014

Lead business analyst responsible for defining, documenting and presenting business requirements for an agent facing application, Aero, utilized by various groups within a matrix organization

- Managed scope across multiple stakeholders within the organization including Management, Business and IT
- Collaborated with third party design vendor and internal design teams to align on new application design while maintaining standards
- Established standards and process for documentation within BA team including test cases, traceability matrix and business requirements

TAHOE PARTNERS

Consultant, Business Analysis | June 2012-March 2013

Responsible for business analysis, requirements engineering and management for major healthcare insurance client, BCBS, focused on re-design of the online member-facing portal

- Managed and aligned goals across multiple work streams including business, tech, & design teams
- Assisted QA team with test case development and execution
- Developed and coordinated user research to validate personas and gathered information about the attributes, goals and motivations of core site users and their high-level desires for features, functions and content

NORTHWESTERN UNIVERSITY

Business Analyst | August 2009-June 2012

Responsible for business analysis and project management for Assessment Center, an online research management tool funded by the National Institutes of Health and utilized by healthcare practitioners and researchers.

- Planned, organized and allocated tasks to developers and quality assurance testers
- Created and managed process for product assets including project plans, requirements documentation, and test cases
- Organized usability workshops, feedback sessions, & surveys to gather user experience stories and requirements for improvements, resulting in greater overall user satisfaction

INTERESTS & HOBBIES

TRAVEL MENTORING

EVENT PLANNING HIKING